♪When sorrow and joy blend into ink♪
♪عندما يمتزج الحزن والفرح في الحبر♪
♪Flowers fade, rain falls, helpless as time♪
تذبل الأزهار، ويهطل المطر، عاجزين كعجز الزمن.
♪Lament this frail body, tangled in love and hate♪
♪رثوا هذا الجسد الهزيل، المتشابك بين الحب والكراهية♪
♪Yet I still wrestle with fate♪
♪ومع ذلك ما زلتُ أصارع القدر♪
♪Snow drifts down, burying all glory♪
♪ يتساقط الثلج، فيدفن كل مجد ♪
♪Blame this destiny granted to me♪
♪ألوم هذا القدر الذي مُنح لي♪
♪Trapped in the chains of love and cause♪
♪محاصرون في قيود الحب والقضية♪
♪When the dust finally settles♪
♪عندما تهدأ الأمور أخيرًا♪
=Glory in Shadows=
=المجد في الظلال=
=Episode 21=
=الحلقة ٢١=
Jingchuan.
جينغتشوان.
Just admit your mistake to Father.
اعترف بخطئك لأبيك.
Why? I've done nothing wrong.
لماذا؟ لم أفعل شيئاً خاطئاً.
Kneel.
اركع.
Hit him.
اضربه.
Hit him hard.
اضربه بقوة.
Father.
أب.
Stop it, Father.
توقف عن ذلك يا أبي.
I beg you, please stop.
أرجوك، توقف.
Stop hitting him.
توقف عن ضربه.
If we don't curb his arrogance now,
إذا لم نكبح جماح غروره الآن،
how will I manage him in the future?
كيف سأتعامل معه في المستقبل؟
♪This life, like foam♪
♪هذه الحياة، مثل الزبد♪
♪The wind is bleak, leaving me alone♪
♪الريح عاتية، تتركني وحيداً♪
♪Drifting with nowhere to anchor♪
♪أُبحر بلا مرسى♪
♪Like falling crimson petals♪
♪كبتلات قرمزية متساقطة♪
Get up, now.
انهض الآن.
If you want to hit me, fine.
إذا كنت تريد ضربي، فلا بأس.
Consider it repaying your care in raising me.
اعتبر ذلك بمثابة رد الجميل لرعايتك لي في تربيتي.
But if you dare lay a hand on Yaochu,
لكن إن تجرأت على إيذاء ياوتشو،
don't blame me for shattering
لا تلومني على التحطيم
what little bond we have left.
ما تبقى لدينا من روابط ضئيلة.
You'd turn on your own father
سوف تنقلب على والدك
for such a woman?
بالنسبة لمثل هذه المرأة؟
Have you no respect for me?
ألا تحترمني؟
A father's kindness breeds a son's respect.
إن لطف الأب يولد احترام الابن.
You once vowed to my mother,
لقد أقسمتَ ذات مرة لأمي،
yet soon after, you cast us aside.
لكن بعد ذلك بوقت قصير، تخليت عنا.
That is heartless.
هذا قسوة قلب.
Zhao Qingru has guarded your family for years.
لقد حمى تشاو تشينغرو عائلتك لسنوات.
Yet you abandoned her.
لكنك تخليت عنها.
That is dishonorable.
هذا أمر مخزٍ.
A man so cold and ungrateful as you
رجلٌ باردٌ وجاحدٌ مثلك
is not worthy of being my father.
لا يستحق أن يكون والدي.
I'm not worthy?
أنا لست جديراً؟
Li Jingchuan.
لي جينغشوان.
Do you believe I'd kill you?
هل تعتقد أنني سأقتلك؟
With your influence,
بفضل نفوذك،
can you even kill me?
هل يمكنك حتى قتلي؟
Dear,
عزيزي،
this time, I'm here for you.
هذه المرة، أنا هنا من أجلك.
Your father hit you today
لقد ضربك والدك اليوم
just to force you into casting me aside.
فقط لأجبرك على التخلي عني.
Even if this hadn't happened,
حتى لو لم يحدث هذا،
he would've found a way to punish me anyway.
كان سيجد طريقة لمعاقبتي على أي حال.
I know you were shielding me.
أعلم أنك كنت تحميني.
And what about you?
وماذا عنك؟
You took the lash for me.
لقد تحملت الجلدة بدلاً مني.
It must have hurt.
لا بد أنه كان مؤلماً.
Yes.
نعم.
My body is wounded.
جسدي مصاب.
But my heart is finally healing.
لكن قلبي بدأ يتعافى أخيراً.
If I hadn't met you,
لو لم أكن قد التقيت بك،
the pain in my heart
الألم في قلبي
might never have eased in this lifetime.
ربما لم تخف حدتها أبداً في هذه الحياة.
And you?
وأنت؟
Would you tell me about the pain in your heart?
هل يمكنك أن تخبرني عن الألم الذي يعتصر قلبك؟
- My mother was sold into a brothel. - I feel cold.
- تم بيع أمي إلى بيت دعارة. - أشعر بالبرد.
That place held her captive for half her life.
لقد احتجزها ذلك المكان لنصف حياتها.
She entrusted her heart to Li Hongshan.
أوكلت قلبها إلى لي هونغشان.
But all she received was deceit and abandonment.
لكن كل ما حصلت عليه كان الخداع والهجر.
And because she was carrying me,
ولأنها كانت تحملني،
she was cast out of the brothel.
طُردت من بيت الدعارة.
My mother knew her days were numbered.
كانت أمي تعلم أن أيامها معدودة.
She feared I'd be left alone.
كانت تخشى أن أبقى وحيداً.
(Li Manor) So, she brought me to Li Manor,
(قصر لي) لذا، أحضرتني إلى قصر لي،
begging Li Hongshan to acknowledge me.
أتوسل إلى لي هونغشان أن يعترف بي.
I can no longer protect you.
لم أعد أستطيع حمايتك.
But if your father accepts you,
لكن إذا قبلك والدك،
I can die
يمكنني أن أموت
without regret.
بلا ندم.
No, I don't want you to die.
لا، لا أريدك أن تموت.
- For his reputation, - Please don't die.
- من أجل سمعته، - أرجوك لا تموت.
Li Hongshan took me in.
استقبلني لي هونغشان.
Our fates are so much alike.
مصائرنا متشابهة للغاية.
Still,
ما زال،
though we've faced countless hardships,
رغم أننا واجهنا مصاعب لا حصر لها،
we both found our way through.
وجدنا طريقنا عبر ذلك.
Right?
يمين؟
(Stability Ensures Peace)
(الاستقرار يضمن السلام)
This Fragrant Concubine Treading on Snow came from Xingwan.
هذه المحظية العطرة التي تدوس على الثلج أتت من شينغوان.
The scent really is identical.
الرائحة متطابقة تماماً.
Is Xingwan truly the murderer?
هل شينغوان هو القاتل حقاً؟
If it were Shopkeeper Liu and Qin Ruoyi,
لو كان الأمر يتعلق بصاحب المتجر ليو وتشين رويي،
she does seem suspicious.
تبدو مثيرة للريبة.
But on the day my mother died,
لكن في اليوم الذي توفيت فيه والدتي،
she stayed with you the whole time.
لقد بقيت معك طوال الوقت.
When would she have had time to kill someone?
متى كان لديها الوقت الكافي لقتل شخص ما؟
That's not right.
هذا ليس صحيحاً.
She wasn't with me the whole time.
لم تكن معي طوال الوقت.
She said she'd pick morning dew to make tea.
قالت إنها ستقطف قطرات الندى الصباحية لتحضير الشاي.
So she left early.
لذا غادرت مبكراً.
When I arrived at Guanyin Nunnery,
عندما وصلت إلى دير غوانيين،
she was already there waiting.
كانت هناك تنتظر بالفعل.
Jingchuan,
جينغتشوان
why join me at the nunnery
لماذا تنضم إليّ في الدير؟
to offer prayers?
لتقديم الصلوات؟
I had nothing else to do, so I came for a stroll.
لم يكن لدي ما أفعله غير ذلك، فجئت في نزهة.
Why didn't you bring Yaochu along?
لماذا لم تحضر ياوتشو معك؟
I see.
أرى.
What do you mean?
ماذا تقصد؟
You're such a fool.
أنت أحمق للغاية.
You really think I killed your mother?
هل تعتقد حقاً أنني قتلت والدتك؟
If that's the case,
إذا كان الأمر كذلك،
Xingwan would be the prime suspect.
سيكون شينغوان المشتبه به الرئيسي.
In this household,
في هذا المنزل،
I keep my guard up with everyone,
أحرص على توخي الحذر مع الجميع.
except Xingwan.
باستثناء شينغوان.
Whenever she appeared,
كلما ظهرت،
she always made me feel
لقد جعلتني أشعر دائمًا
she was pure and kind-hearted.
كانت نقية القلب وطيبة القلب.
But if it was all just an act,
لكن إذا كان كل ذلك مجرد تمثيل،
that would be truly frightening.
سيكون ذلك مرعباً حقاً.
Xingwan was taken in before I returned.
تم القبض على شينغوان قبل عودتي.
Zhao Qingru had just given birth to Li Jingxu
كان Zhao Qingru قد أنجب للتو Li Jingxu
and nearly died in childbirth.
وكادت تموت أثناء الولادة.
She kept a young girl nearby to bring some joy,
أبقت فتاة صغيرة قريبة منها لتجلب بعض البهجة،
but since she wasn't a real Li,
لكن بما أنها لم تكن لي حقيقية،
she was bullied everywhere she went.
كانت تتعرض للتنمر أينما ذهبت.
So, she followed me from a young age.
لذا، فقد تبعتني منذ صغرها.
In my eyes,
في نظري،
she had always been timid and weak.
لطالما كانت خجولة وضعيفة.
Was that just a disguise?
هل كان ذلك مجرد تمويه؟
I must've overlooked something.
لا بد أنني أغفلت شيئاً.
In such a scheming household,
في مثل هذا المنزل المليء بالمكائد،
she grew up safely.
لقد نشأت بأمان.
How could she be simple?
كيف يمكن أن تكون بسيطة؟
But she bore no grudge against my mother.
لكنها لم تحمل أي ضغينة ضد والدتي.
Why would she want her dead?
لماذا تريد موتها؟
Why don't we just ask her?
لماذا لا نسألها مباشرة؟
Wait.
انتظر.
Right now, our only lead is the scent.
في الوقت الحالي، خيطنا الوحيد هو الرائحة.
If Xingwan really did it,
إذا كان شينغوان هو من فعل ذلك بالفعل،
she could easily claim that Concubine Tang is slandering her
بإمكانها بسهولة أن تدّعي أن المحظية تانغ تشوه سمعتها
and refuse to admit it.
ويرفضون الاعتراف بذلك.
If it wasn't her,
لو لم تكن هي،
wouldn't that harm your bond as siblings?
ألن يضر ذلك بعلاقتكما كأخوين؟
Besides, the Fan Scorpion Poison hasn't been found.
إلى جانب ذلك، لم يتم العثور على سم العقرب المروحي .
Let's not alert her just yet.
لا داعي لإبلاغها الآن.
Then what should we do now?
إذن، ماذا يجب أن نفعل الآن؟
Find someone
ابحث عن شخص ما
to follow her quietly.
أن يتبعها بهدوء.
Let's see if she does anything suspicious
لنرى ما إذا كانت ستفعل أي شيء مريب
and check
وتحقق
whether she really has the Fan Scorpion Poison.
ما إذا كانت مصابة بالفعل بسم عقرب المروحة.
Alright.
على ما يرام.
Wait.
انتظر.
General.
عام.
What's inside here?
ما الذي يوجد بالداخل هنا؟
This...
هذا...
It's a calming potion.
إنه مشروب مهدئ.
My lady hasn't been sleeping well.
زوجتي لا تنام جيداً.
So, we asked a physician to prepare it.
لذلك، طلبنا من طبيب أن يقوم بتحضيره.
Go on.
هيا.
Yes.
نعم.
Jingchuan.
جينغتشوان.
I saw your maid take medicine out.
رأيت خادمتك وهي تخرج الدواء.
Why?
لماذا؟
Are you feeling unwell?
هل تشعر بتوعك؟
I've been waking up suddenly at night.
أستيقظ فجأة في الليل.
So, I drank some calming potion.
لذا، شربت بعضاً من المشروب المهدئ.
It's nothing serious.
لا شيء خطير.
Jingchuan,
جينغتشوان
has your injury healed?
هل شفيت إصابتك؟
I was just about to visit you.
كنت على وشك زيارتك.
It's fine.
لا بأس.
Jingchuan,
جينغتشوان
I know you don't like Father.
أعلم أنك لا تحب أبي.
But what Father said
لكن ما قاله أبي
does make some sense.
هذا منطقي إلى حد ما.
Xingwan,
شينغوان،
you should know
يجب أن تعلم
Yaochu and I love each other.
أنا وياوتشو نحب بعضنا البعض.
I'd never cast my wife aside for ambition.
لن أتخلى عن زوجتي أبداً من أجل الطموح.
Jingchuan,
جينغتشوان
you and Yaochu are so sweet.
أنت وياوتشو لطيفان للغاية.
My Lady!
سيدتي!
My Lady,
سيدتي،
the Master has asked for you.
لقد طلب السيد حضورك.
Understood.
مفهوم.
Does he call you over every day?
هل يتصل بك كل يوم؟
Father just woke up
استيقظ الأب للتو
and was met with sudden troubles at home.
وواجه مشاكل مفاجئة في المنزل.
It's left him troubled.
لقد تركه ذلك في حالة من القلق.
He's asked me to speak with him often.
لقد طلب مني التحدث معه كثيراً.
Go on then.
هيا بنا إذن.
What's this?
ما هذا؟
I followed Zhenzhu all the way.
لقد اتبعت تشنزو طوال الطريق.
I saw her toss the leftover herbs in a hidden spot
رأيتها وهي ترمي الأعشاب المتبقية في مكان مخفي
and step on them to bits.
واسحقهم إرباً إرباً.
I picked the remnants back up
التقطت البقايا مرة أخرى
and went to consult a physician.
وذهب لاستشارة طبيب.
The potion turned out to be...
اتضح أن الجرعة كانت...
Tell us.
أخبرنا.
It was a contraceptive potion.
كان ذلك مشروباً مانعاً للحمل.
My Lady,
سيدتي،
that potion is bad for your health.
هذا المشروب ضار بصحتك.
Shall I fetch the physician to examine you?
هل أحضر الطبيب ليفحصك؟
Do you want everyone
هل تريد الجميع؟
to know about my shame?
هل تريد أن تعرف عن خجلي؟
I would never dare.
لن أجرؤ على ذلك أبداً.
Leave at once.
يغادر في وقت واحد.
Only when pain cuts deep into the bones
فقط عندما يتغلغل الألم عميقاً في العظام
can hatred last forever.
هل يمكن للكراهية أن تدوم إلى الأبد؟
Why would she drink such a thing?
لماذا تشرب مثل هذا الشيء؟
Could it be she...
هل يمكن أن تكون هي...
This matter must never be revealed.
يجب ألا يتم الكشف عن هذا الأمر أبداً.
Yes.
نعم.
Leave.
يترك.
She rarely socializes with anyone.
نادراً ما تختلط بأحد.
How could that be?
كيف يمكن أن يكون ذلك؟
Given the situation,
بالنظر إلى الوضع،
they've been in contact for quite some time.
لقد كانوا على اتصال لفترة طويلة.
Even if she was secretly seeing someone,
حتى لو كانت على علاقة سرية بشخص ما،
why would she kill someone?
لماذا قد تقتل شخصاً ما؟
That depends
هذا يعتمد
on who her lover is.
حول هوية حبيبها.
(Qifang Pavilion)
(جناح كيفانغ)
These past few days,
خلال الأيام القليلة الماضية،
she hasn't reached out to anyone outside?
ألم تتواصل مع أي شخص من خارجها؟
I've been following her.
لقد كنت أتابعها.
I even checked everything going in and out of her room,
بل إنني فحصت كل شيء يدخل ويخرج من غرفتها،
but found nothing suspicious.
لكن لم يتم العثور على أي شيء مثير للريبة.
Could it be
هل يمكن أن يكون
that this person is inside the manor?
هل هذا الشخص موجود داخل القصر؟
Wait...
انتظر...
What is it?
ما هذا؟
Impossible.
مستحيل.
That's absolutely impossible.
هذا مستحيل تماماً.
(Stability Ensures Peace)
(الاستقرار يضمن السلام)
♪New snow falls thick beneath the eaves♪
♪يتساقط الثلج الجديد بكثافة تحت حواف السقف♪
♪Covering the courtyard gate♪
♪تغطية بوابة الفناء♪
♪Your gaze melts winter into spring♪
♪نظرتك تذيب الشتاء في الربيع♪
♪Turning back from the boundless multitude♪
♪العودة من بين الجموع التي لا حدود لها♪
♪Gazing at you in that fleeting moment♪
♪أنظر إليك في تلك اللحظة العابرة♪
♪All the hardships fade into drifting dust♪
♪تتلاشى كل المصاعب في غبار متناثر♪
♪A foolish dream turns earnest with you in it♪
♪حلمٌ ساذجٌ يتحول إلى حلمٍ جادٍّ بوجودك فيه♪
♪Even a feigned play can grow into true affection♪
♪حتى التمثيل المصطنع يمكن أن يتحول إلى عاطفة حقيقية♪
♪Too many dusks walked alone beneath my umbrella♪
♪كثير من الغسقات سارت وحيدة تحت مظلتي♪
♪Yet I crave the warmth left in your embrace♪
♪لكنني أتوق إلى الدفء المتبقي في حضنك♪
♪Among thousands of bright lamps, is there one♪
♪من بين آلاف المصابيح الساطعة، هل يوجد واحد؟♪
♪That waits quietly for me?♪
♪هل ينتظرني بصمت؟♪
♪Time grinds through the rings of memory♪
♪ يمر الوقت سريعاً عبر حلقات الذاكرة ♪
♪Only you keep me warm in the long night♪
♪أنتِ وحدكِ من تُدفئينني في الليل الطويل♪
♪Scars left by the days gone by♪
♪ندوبٌ خلّفتها الأيام الخوالي♪
♪Lie upon the lines of our hands together♪
♪استلقوا على خطوط أيدينا معًا♪
♪I hold out a heart sincere and true♪
♪أُخرج قلباً صادقاً وحقيقياً♪
♪Crossing the deep courtyard♪
♪عبور الفناء العميق♪
♪Just to trade it for one kiss from you♪
♪فقط لأستبدلها بقبلة واحدة منك♪
♪Praying our hair turns gray without regret♪
♪ندعو أن يتحول شعرنا إلى اللون الرمادي دون ندم♪
♪So that true love will finally come to be♪
♪حتى يتحقق الحب الحقيقي في النهاية♪